💌 FrostBDonovan@gmail.com | 🧥 fdonovan98.github.io/portfolio | 🛆 frostdonovan | 🛅 frost-donovan | 🖸 FDonovan98

Summary.

I am an artist with a non-traditional background, coming from programming and production. I fell in love with game art while working as a producer alongside artists creating and publishing games during my undergrad, and since have been pursuing a masters in game art. My background gives me an aptitude for picking up and learning new software and technical principles quickly, and I have excelled at learning, adapting, and experimenting with new workflows. My production experience has given me a strong grounding in agile methodology and helped train my flexibility, helping me understand and utilise the different stages of production, and helping me communicate and work well in a team of mixed skills and abilities.

Like most people in games, I'm a massive nerd. I love film, and love how my masters has given me a deeper appreciation for the medium as I started to learn and analyse how composition and especially lighting were set up in a shot and why. I've also got into Warhammer 40k for it's deep and at times wildly over the top lore, and have recently bought a 3D printer, which may be the coolest purchase I've ever made.

Skills

- Art Software: Maya, zBrush, Substance Designer, Substance Painter, Blender
- · Game Engines: Unreal Engine 5, Unreal Engine 4, Unity
- · Agile Management: User Stories, Story Points, Velocity, Sprint & Release Planning & Review, Scrum, CD Pipelines
- Software: Jira, Confluence, Git, Trello, GitHub & Bitbucket, Google & Microsoft Suite
- Languages: C#, C++, Latex, Github Actions

Published Games ____

Castan - Producer

Unity 2020.3 September 2021 - May 2022

SELF PUBLISHED TO STEAM (HTTPS://STORE.STEAMPOWERED.COM/APP/1836170/CASTAN/)

- Utilised Story Points & Velocity, Release Planning, and Jira to manage scope
- Facilitated & assisted with several significant redesigns
- · Developed a Github Action workflow to automatically build, test & publish daily builds to Steam

Carma - Producer Unity 2019.4

SELF PUBLISHED TO STEAM (HTTPS://STORE.STEAMPOWERED.COM/APP/1603990/CARMA/)

Published June 2021

- Shortlisted for the Grads In Games Student Game Award
- · Worked with a multidisciplinary team to bring Carma from concept to published game
- Planned sprints and development milestones using Agile
- Removed blockers and streamlined development pipelines
- · Focused on maintaining team health and reinforcing healthy working practices
- Set up Steam store and maintained updated builds

Awards_

Finalist, Grads In Games Student Game Award

Education

Falmouth University

MA GAME ART

Falmouth, United Kingdom

· Liaised with technical staff to secure further education on physical lighting techniques for myself and peers

September 2022 - August 2023

Falmouth University

BSc Computing For Games

Falmouth, United Kingdom

September 2019 - June 2022

- · Worked with multi-discipline teams to bring several games through a full development cycle
- Published two to Steam, one of which was shortlisted for Grads In Games Student Game Award
- · Wrote a dissertation on Continuous Delivery (CD) In Student Teams, implementing and analysing the effect of CD pipelines
- Graduated with a 2.1 Honours

Work Experience _____

FROST DONOVAN · RÉSUMÉ JANUARY 30, 2023

Director Falmouth, Cornwall

GLASS NOMAD GAMES

• Started a company to publish video games my team and I were developing

- Managed company accounts and government-required paperwork
- Handled Steam registration, set up, and backend work for multiple titles

Transfer eteam 198. eteam 198. eteap, and backeria Work 191 material action

Senior Ambassador

Falmouth, Cornwall

March 2021 - Current

June 2020 - September 2021

FXPLUS

- Responsible for the smooth running of events
- Managed the distribution of Student Ambassadors during events
- Relied on to handle any complications or problems that arose during an event